cross.com 2019-06-17

# Privacy & Security | Cross - US

At A. T. Cross, we are deeply committed to respecting the privacy of our customers, and to safeguarding your personal information online.

## Introduction

This Privacy Policy forms part of the Terms and covers the A.T. Cross website which may be accessed via, www.cross.com (the "Website") and the Services provided through it. It describes how We collect, protect and use information We receive from Website visitors.

## Information We collect

We collect different forms of information, depending on the part of the Website being visited. We may collect personal information from you when you place an order, send email enquiries register for an event, provide feedback, place a publication order, or participate in another part of the Website.

We may ask you for personal information such as your name, email address, postal address, postcode, job title, daytime and/or mobile phone number, credit/debit card information (when ordering products or booking Services only) and information about your workplace and the nature of your business. You must also provide us with personal information when you create a user name and password. You may also voluntarily provide Us with personal information about any special needs you may have so that we can try to ensure Our Services meet your requirements.

If you wish to make a complaint about an employment right or you are responding to a complaint, We will collect relevant information including personal information in order to assist you. This information will also help us to monitor progress and to produce anonymised statistics. The information We collect in this context may be disclosed to assist in research into the use and effectiveness of our products and services.

You may, however, visit parts of the Website anonymously and without registering. If you choose not to register on the Website you may not be able to use the Website and its features to their fullest extent. Registering with Cross.com makes shopping online faster and more convenient, and allows us to provide you with access to special offers and promotions, previews of new products, and other valuable features.

If you have previously registered with Cross.com or have purchased from us in the past, you may choose at any time to discontinue receiving further promotional information from us or our trusted partners.

If you currently have a Cross.com account, you may update or correct any registration information previously provided within the My Account section of our web site. If you wish to update your e-mail preferences only, simply indicate your new preferences on our email preferences form.

## Use of personal information

We use the personal information We collect for the purposes of:

  * providing, developing, improving and personalising Our Services and the Website
  * providing you with information about Our Services
  * dealing with your inquiries and requests
  * administering orders and accounts relating to Our customers
  * administering user accounts
  * generating anonymous reports about use of the Website and its features

We may use the personal information collected via the Website to provide you with mailings for marketing purposes or to inform you of Our promotions or changes to Our Services. If you register on the Website We may use the personal information We collect to send you information about Our Services by email. You may opt out of receiving information about Our Services by selecting the relevant option on Cross.com or by sending Us an email at : consumerre@cross.com.

## Security and confidentiality

Verisign™ safeguards the security of the personal information you provide to Us with physical, electronic and managerial procedures. We use industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all pages where We collect personal information.

Any personal information you provide will be held securely and your personal information will not be sold or traded to third parties. In some circumstances We may need to disclose your personal information (i) to a third party to provide a service you have requested, (ii) to fulfil a request for information, (iii) to comply with a legal requirement or request from a competent court, regulator or other authority, or (iv) if We believe that there has been a violation of the Terms, of Our rights or the rights of any third party. Any information about you that We pass to a third party service provider will be held securely by that party and used only to provide the services or information you have requested. If for any reason you feel uncomfortable shopping with us online, we invite you to visit an authorized A. T. Cross retailer near you or to call us and order by phone at 1.800.282.7677 in the United States (from Monday through Friday, 9 a.m. through 5 p.m. Eastern time).

## Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data sent to your computer when you visit the Website and which enable Us to collect information about you. They are stored in the cookie directory of your hard-drive, and do not necessarily expire at the end of your session although session cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. The information We collect in this way may include data about how you use the Website, information about your computer (including your IP address and browser type), demographic data and, if you visited the Website by clicking on a link from a different website, the URL of that website. We may also collect information about your online activity, such as the pages you have viewed and the purchases you have made. Our use of cookies also allows registered users of the Website to be presented with a personalised version of the Website, to carry out transactions and to have access to information about their account.

Although your browser may be set up to allow the creation of cookies, you can specify that you wish to be prompted before a website puts a cookie on your hard drive, so that you can decide whether to allow it. Alternatively, you can set your computer not to accept any cookies. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen for information about how to do this. If you disable cookies, you may not have access to certain features that make your experience of the Website more efficient and some of Our Services may not function properly, such as placing an online order. Visitors who disable cookies can still place orders over the telephone and by email and fax.

## Social networking

Cross.com may offer you the opportunity to share or follow information about the Website (or the products and/or services available through it) using third party social networking functionality (such as through "share this", "like" or "follow" buttons).

We offer this functionality in order to generate interest in Cross.com among the members of your social networks, and to permit you to share and follow opinions, news and recommendations about the Website with your friends. However, you should be aware that sharing personal or non-personal information with a social network may result in that information being collected by the social network provider or result in that information being made publicly-available, including through Internet search engines.

Please note that We do not exercise any endorse or control the policies or practices of any third party social network whose functionality you may access through Cross.com. You should always read the privacy policy of any social network through which you share information carefully in order to understand their specific privacy and information usage practices.

## Access to your information and contacting Us

You have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. Please address requests (with a return email address where possible) to:

Email: consumerre@cross.com

If you have a query or complaint about this Privacy Policy or about the Website, you can contact Us at consumerre@cross.com.

## Links to external sites from the Website

The Website contains links to other websites, mainly government departments, but also to those of other third parties. These websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy and our company is not responsible for the privacy practices within any of these other websites. You should be aware of this when you leave the Website and We encourage you to read the privacy statements of other websites.

## Internet based transfers

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal information necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Territories outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") may not have laws which provide the same level of protection for personal information as those inside the EEA. However, if We process your personal information on servers or use third party service providers based in such territories, We will endeavour to ensure that your personal information is afforded the same level of protection as in the EEA. By visiting the Website and communicating electronically with Us, you acknowledge Our processing of personal information in this way.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

If this Privacy Policy changes in any way, We will place an updated version on this webpage. If you do not agree with the changes We make please do not continue to use the Website. Regularly reviewing this webpage ensures you are always aware of what information We collect, how We use it and under what circumstances, if any, We will share it with other parties.

Effective: May 21st, 2018
